So, let's step a step back and look at what we've achieved.
我们回顾下所学的知识
We knew there was a measurement update,
我们知道有测量校正
an emotion update, which is also called prediction.
动作校正 也称为预测
We know that the measurement update is implemented by
我们知道测量校正是通过乘法实现的
multiplication which is the same as Bayes rule.
和贝叶斯规则一样
The motion update is done by total probability or an addition.
动作校正通过总概率或加法实现
So, we tackle the more complicated case,
我们解决了更复杂的情形
this is actually the hop from mathematically,
这一步实际上从数学角度来讲很复杂
and we solve this, we give an exact expression.
我们解决了 得出了精确的表达式
We even derived mathematically,
甚至通过数学方式进行了推理
and you were able to write
你能够写一个
a computer program that implements this step of the Kalman Filter.
实现卡尔曼滤波器这一步的计算机程序
I don't want to go into too much depth here.
这一步我不打算详细讲解了
This is a really, really easy step.
它是一个非常非常简单的步骤
Let me write it down for you.
我直接写出来
Suppose you live in a world like this,
假设处于这样的环境中
this is your current best estimate of where you are and this is your uncertainty.
这是当前的最佳位置预测 这是不确定性
Now, say you move to the right side,
现在假设以一定的距离移到了右侧
a certain distance, and that motion itself has its own set of uncertainty.
动作本身有自己的不确定性
Then you arrive at a prediction that adds the motion command to the mean,
然后得出了预测 将动作部分加到均值上
and it has an increased uncertainty over the initial uncertainty.
不确定性比初始不确定性更高
Intuitively, this makes sense.
直观地来讲 这是合理的
If you move to the right by this distance in
如果你向右移动这么长的距离
expectation you're exactly where you wish to be,
期望正好抵达要去的地方
but you've lost information because your motion
但是丢失了信息
tends to lose information as manifest by this uncertainty over here.
因为动作倾向于丢失信息 这里的不确定性体现了这一点
Now, the math for this is really, really easy.
数学部分非常非常简单
A new mean, is your old mean plus the motion often called u.
新均值等于旧均值加上动作（通常称为 u）
So, if you move over 10 meters,
如果移动 10 米
this will be 10 meters and you knew sigma square is
这个将是 10 米
your old sigma square plus variance of the motion Gaussian.
我们知道 σ2 等于旧 σ2 加上动作高斯函数的方差
This is all you need to know,
只需知道这些信息
it's just an addition,
就是一个加法
and I won't prove it to you because it's really trivial.
我不证明了 因为很简单
But in summary, we have a Gaussian over here.
总之 这里有个高斯函数
We have a Gaussian for the motion with u as
这是动作高斯函数 均值是 u
the mean and r square has its own motion uncertainty.
r2 有自己的动作不确定性
The resulting Gaussian in the prediction step just adds these two things up,
预测步骤生成的高斯函数直接将这两项相加
mu plus u and sigma square plus r square.
μ + u 以及 σ2 + r2
Since it was so simple, let me quiz you,
因为太简单了 做道练习吧
we have a Gaussian before
在预测步骤之前有个高斯函数
the prediction step which mu equals 8 and sigma square equals 4.
μ = 8 σ2 = 4
We then move to the right,
然后往右移动
a total of 10 with a motion uncertainty of 6.
总共移动了 10 米 动作不确定性是 6
Now, describe to me the predicted Gaussian
请描述下预测高斯函数
and give me the new mu and the new sigma square.
算出新的 μ 和 σ2 的值